So here is a question that can come up
Đây là câu hỏi có thể xuất hiện
in the exam.
trong kỳ thi.
This is around the process to share an AMI
Đó là quy trình chia sẻ một AMI
with another account, and the AMI has been encrypted
với tài khoản khác khi AMI đã được mã hóa
with a KMS key.
bằng khóa KMS.
So the AMI is in your source account,
AMI nằm trong tài khoản nguồn,
and it's encrypted with your KMS key.
và được mã hóa bằng khóa KMS của bạn.
So how do you launch an EC2 instance
Vậy làm sao khởi chạy EC2
in account B from the AMI in account A?
ở tài khoản B từ AMI ở tài khoản A?
So first you must modify the AMI property
Trước tiên bạn phải chỉnh thuộc tính AMI
with a launch permission, and the list launch permission
với launch permission, thêm quyền launch
allows account B to launch this AMI.
cho phép tài khoản B khởi chạy AMI này.
So effectively, this is how you share an AMI.
Đó là cách bạn chia sẻ AMI.
You must modify the launch permissions
Bạn phải sửa launch permission
and add the specified target to its account ID.
và thêm ID tài khoản đích.
Then you need to also share the KMS key
Sau đó bạn cũng cần chia sẻ khóa KMS
for the accounts B to be able to use it.
để tài khoản B có thể dùng nó.
So this is done usually with a key policy.
Việc này thường thực hiện qua key policy.
Then in account B, you would create an IAM role
Rồi ở tài khoản B, bạn tạo IAM role
or IAM user with enough permissions to actually
hoặc IAM user với đủ quyền
use both the KMS key and the AMI.
để dùng cả khóa KMS lẫn AMI.
So you must have it on the KMS side, access to the
Vì vậy phía KMS bạn cần quyền
Describekey API call, the ReEncrypted API call,
Describekey, ReEncrypt, CreateGrant và Decrypt.
CreateGrant and Decrypt API calls.
Khi mọi thứ xong, bạn có thể khởi chạy
And then once all of this is done, you can simply launch
EC2 từ AMI đó và tùy chọn
an EC2 instance from that AMI and optionally
tài khoản đích có thể mã hóa lại mọi thứ
the target accounts can choose to re-encrypt everything
bằng khóa KMS của riêng họ
with the KMS key that it's owned, that it owns
để mã hóa lại các volume.
in its own accounts, to re-encrypt the volumes.
Và bạn đã có thể khởi chạy EC2.
But there you go, you can launch an EC2 instance.
Hiểu quy trình này là bạn đã sẵn sàng
And so if you understand this process you're good to go
trả lời câu hỏi trong kỳ thi.
to maybe answer one question at the exam.
Hy vọng bạn thích và hẹn gặp lại ở bài tiếp theo.